<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microservices on Vlad Khononov</title>
    <link>https://vladikk.com/categories/Microservices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microservices on Vlad Khononov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vladikk.com/categories/Microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-Driven Architecture on AWS: The Basics</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/2024/09/28/aws-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/2024/09/28/aws-eda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The abundance of services provided by AWS often makes it possible to implement the same functionality in different ways. In the case of messaging systems, AWS offers services such as Simple Notification Service (SNS), Simple Queue Service (SQS), EventBridge, Kinesis, and Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK). It may seem that at least a subset of these services duplicates the same functionality. In this post, I want to describe my go-to architecture and explain why, in my opinion, it is the simplest, most cost-effective, and robust solution for the majority of cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-driven-architecture&#34;&gt;Event-Driven Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components of an event-driven system communicate by publishing and subscribing to events. The asynchronous integration offers significant non-functional advantages. For example, it decouples the integrated components’ lifecycles. To a certain degree, the system can keep functioning even in the face of unavailability of some of its services, thus also reducing the coordination overhead needed to deploy updated components, and to evolve the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic event-driven integration is comprised of two parts: a component of the system can publish events describing important occurrences in its lifecycle, and it can react (subscribe) to events published by other parts of the system. Let’s see what managed services we can leverage for implementing this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Microservices, or Balancing Complexity in Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/2020/04/09/untangling-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/2020/04/09/untangling-microservices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vladikk.com/images/untangling-microservices/header.png&#34; alt=&#34;Untangling Microservices, or Balancing Complexity in Distributed Systems&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The microservices honeymoon period is over. Uber is refactoring thousands of microservices into a more manageable solution [1]; Kelsey Hightower is predicting monoliths are the future [2]; and even Sam Newman is declaring that microservices should never be the default choice, but rather a last resort [3].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s going on here? Why have so many projects become unmaintainable, despite microservices’ promise of simplicity and flexibility? Or are monoliths better, after all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I want to address these questions. You will learn about common design issues that turn microservices into distributed big balls of mud – and, of course, how you can avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Pattern: Optimistic Consistency</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/2019/04/18/optimistic-consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/2019/04/18/optimistic-consistency/</guid>
      <description>Ladies and Gentlemen, lo and behold a new consistency model - “Optimistic Consistency”. Implementation of this pattern is quite simple: commit as many transactions as you want, against as many storage mechanisms as you need. That’s all. Let’s see an example.
Example Say as the result of some user’s operation the system has to:
 Modify data in MongoDB Publish some events to Kafka Update search model in Elasticsearch; and Execute an operation on some remote system  You implement this logic by executing those operations one after another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Complexity in Microservices</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/2018/02/28/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/2018/02/28/microservices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vladikk.com/images/microservices/title-img.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tackling Complexity in Microservices&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservices have taken our industry by storm. Teams around the world have ditched their clumsy monoliths in favor of chasing the dream of loosely coupled, manageable, and independently deployable microservices. Unfortunately, many of them ended up worse off than they were before - in the realm of distributed monoliths. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I had an hour to solve a problem I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about  the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions” - Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this quote is the key to solving most of the issues we have when designing microservices-based systems. We rush into solutions without ensuring we know what exactly a microservice is. In this post, I’d like to take a stab at answering this question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Contexts are NOT Microservices</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/2018/01/21/bounded-contexts-vs-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vlad Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/2018/01/21/bounded-contexts-vs-microservices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vladikk.com/images/bc-ms/rebel-scum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rebel scum&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always considered Domain-Driven Design’s Bounded Context as a guideline for defining the boundaries of Microservices. I was wrong. Not only is this heuristic flawed, but Bounded Contexts are the exact opposite of Microservices! To explain this point of view, I’ll start with a quick refresh of what Bounded Contexts are; then I’ll discuss the relationship between Bounded Contexts and Microservices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>