<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Thoughts | Vladikk]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.vladikk.com/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.vladikk.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-07T11:55:53+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.vladikk.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vladik Khononov]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vladik@khononov.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quick and Dirty Hack for Interviewing Job Candidates]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.vladikk.com/2016/03/05/interviewing/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-05T16:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.vladikk.com/2016/03/05/interviewing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One simple question can shed a lot of light on one’s competency in a given field: "On a scale of 1 to 10, please rate your knowledge of [enter-name-of-the-field-here]".</p>

<p>One can assume that the higher the grade, the better. But that’s not the case at all. Why? Science — that’s why. Enter the Dunning-Kruger effect.</p>

<h2>The Dunning-Kruger Effect</h2>

<p>The Dunning-Kruger effect is a cognitive bias that suggests that one cannot objectively assess one's own abilities. It’s all about the unknowns — things that you don’t know — and whether you're aware of them.</p>

<p>The less expertise you have in a given field, the more unknown unknowns you have. You cannot objectively evaluate your knowledge, and, consequently, you are mistakenly assessing your abilities to be much higher than they actually are.</p>

<p>This bias also works the other way around. The more expertise you have in a given field, the more known unknowns you have. This awareness of things you don't know tricks you into making a more humbling assessment of your abilities.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A more formal explanation can be found on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect">Wikipedia</a>.</p>

<h2>What Answers to Look For?</h2>

<p>According to the Dunning-Kruger effect, it's safe to say that you should beware of the answers that rate below 4 or above 8. And run for your life if the answer is greater than 10!</p>

<p>The 5-7 range is the sweet spot.</p>

<p>Also, there's one more answer to look for: an inquiry to define what level of competency merits a 10.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
