<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Vladikk</title>
    <link>https://vladikk.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Vladikk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vladikk.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a software engineer with 20 years of industry experience. During the years, I worked for companies large and small, in roles ranging from Webmaster to Chief Architect. I aim to maintain an active media career as a public speaker, a blogger, and an author. Currently I’m a regular speaker at leading software engineering conferences, such as O’Reilly Software Architecture, NDC, DDD Europe, and others. My topics include distributed systems, Domain-Driven Design, microservices, evolutionary architecture, and software architecture in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/books/</guid>
      <description>Domain-Driven Design: The First 15 Years I was honored to participate in this project, alongside Martin Fowler, Mel Conway, Rebecca Wirfs-Brock, and other industry leaders:

Coming Soon Currently I&amp;rsquo;m working on a new writing project for a prominent publishing company. More information coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/consulting/</guid>
      <description>Consulting My core areas of expertise include domain-driven design, microservices, event sourcing, event storming, CQRS, and distributed systems. I can help you to:
 Develop a strategy for incremental refactoring of monolithic codebases into modular microservice-based systems Build an architectural strategy for a startup company Document and manage software architecture Align software architecture with business needs Recover business logic buried in legacy codebases Migrate legacy systems to cloud infrastructure  On-Site Training I can provide training adapted to your company&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>For any type of enquiry, you can contact me via either of the methods below:
 Email: vladik at khononov.com Twitter: @vladikk Github: vladikk Facebook: vladikk Linkedin: vladikkhononov  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/reading/</guid>
      <description>A More Beautiful Question: The Power of Inquiry to Spark Breakthrough Ideas The Goal: A Process of Ongoing ImprovementBeyond the Goal: Eliyahu Goldratt Speaks on the Theory of Constraints (Your Coach In A Box)The Choice, Revised EditionDomain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of SoftwareImplementing Domain-Driven DesignScrum: The Art of Doing Twice the Work in Half the TimeFlow: Living at the Peak of Your AbilitiesThe Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business WinSapiens: A Brief History of HumankindThe Obstacle Is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into TriumphSimple Rules: How to Thrive in a Complex WorldGetting to Yes: Negotiating Agreement Without Giving InBorn to Run: A Hidden Tribe, Superathletes, and the Greatest Race the World Has Never SeenThe Lean Startup: How Today&amp;rsquo;s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful BusinessesBusiness Model Generation: A Handbook for Visionaries, Game Changers, and ChallengersDrive: The Surprising Truth About What Motivates UsEnterprise Integration Patterns: Designing, Building, and Deploying Messaging SolutionsWorking Effectively with Legacy CodePatterns of Enterprise Application ArchitectureThinking, Fast and Slow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking</title>
      <link>https://vladikk.com/page/speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>https://vladikk.com/page/speaking/</guid>
      <description>During the last few years I spoke at leading software engineering conferences, e.g. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Software Architecture, NDC, DDD Europe, and more. My topics include Domain-Driven Design, microservices, TDD, modular design, evolutionary architecture, and software arechitecture in general.
Feel free to reach out if you&amp;rsquo;d like me to speak at your conference or on-site event.
Upcoming Events 11/06/2019: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Software Architecture Conference 2019 7 Years of DDD: Tackling Complexity in Large-Scale Marketing Systems Microservices, Bounded Contexts, and Everything In Between Location: San Jose, CA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>