<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Vladikk</title>
    <link>http://www.vladikk.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Vladikk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.vladikk.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://www.vladikk.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>http://www.vladikk.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Having over 18 years of experience in the software industry, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked across multiple business domains, including advertisement, healthcare, telecommunications, and customer acquisition. Currently I serve as the Chief Architect for Internovus, where I&amp;rsquo;m in charge of large-scale projects, and an international developers team.
My main areas of interest are Domain-Driven Design, Distributed Systems, Cloud Computing and building effective teams.
When I&amp;rsquo;m not geeking out, I read lots of books, photograph nature, and repair my r/c aircrafts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://www.vladikk.com/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>http://www.vladikk.com/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>For any type of enquiry, you can contact me via either of the methods below:
 Email: vladik at khononov.com Twitter: @vladikk Github: vladikk Facebook: vladikk Linkedin: vladikkhononov  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>http://www.vladikk.com/page/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>http://www.vladikk.com/page/reading/</guid>
      <description>A More Beautiful Question: The Power of Inquiry to Spark Breakthrough Ideas The Goal: A Process of Ongoing ImprovementBeyond the Goal: Eliyahu Goldratt Speaks on the Theory of Constraints (Your Coach In A Box)The Choice, Revised EditionDomain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of SoftwareImplementing Domain-Driven DesignScrum: The Art of Doing Twice the Work in Half the TimeFlow: Living at the Peak of Your AbilitiesThe Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business WinSapiens: A Brief History of HumankindThe Obstacle Is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into TriumphSimple Rules: How to Thrive in a Complex WorldGetting to Yes: Negotiating Agreement Without Giving InBorn to Run: A Hidden Tribe, Superathletes, and the Greatest Race the World Has Never SeenThe Lean Startup: How Today&amp;rsquo;s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful BusinessesBusiness Model Generation: A Handbook for Visionaries, Game Changers, and ChallengersDrive: The Surprising Truth About What Motivates UsEnterprise Integration Patterns: Designing, Building, and Deploying Messaging SolutionsWorking Effectively with Legacy CodePatterns of Enterprise Application ArchitectureThinking, Fast and Slow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking</title>
      <link>http://www.vladikk.com/page/speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vladik@khononov.com (Vladik Khononov)</author>
      <guid>http://www.vladikk.com/page/speaking/</guid>
      <description>01/20/2018: DDD Europe 2018 Tackling Complexity in Marketing Systems Location: Amsterdam, Netherlands
Language: English
13/12/2017: Code Europe 7 Years of DDD: Tackling Complexity in Large-Scale Marketing Systems NDepend - Siri for Software Engineers Location: Wroclaw, Poland
Language: English
17/11/2017: ISTA 2017 How to Tame TDD Location: Sofia, Bulgaria
Language: English
20/10/2017: KanDDDinsky Tackling Complexity in DDD, CQRS, and Event Sourcing Location: Berlin, Germany
Language: English
21/09/2017: Explore DDD Tackling Complexity In Large-Scale Marketing Systems Location: Denver, CO, USA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>